newdirectionsaromatics.com 2014-07-06

# Essential Oils, Aromatherapy, Candle, Soap, Cosmetic & Spa Supplies | New Directions Aromatics

##  Our Privacy Commitment 

At NDA we know how important it is to protect your personal information. Whether you are shopping with us online or in person we want to make every customer experience safe and secure. In keeping with that goal, we have developed this Privacy Policy to explain our practices for the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information.

This Policy applies to our Web Sites, in-store pick ups, and all other channels in which NDA collects and uses your personal information.

[[Back to Top]](http://www.newdirectionsaromatics.com/#)

##  What Information is Collected? 

At NDA, we collect two types of information: personal information and non-personal information. The types of information we collect depend on the nature of your interaction with us.

**Personal information**

Personal information is information that can identify an individual or information about an identifiable individual. We may collect personal information such as:

  * Your contact information - e.g., name, postal address, telephone number, and email address;
  * Your transaction information - e.g., products purchased, method of payment, amount paid, and credit or debit card number.

**Non-personal information**

Non-personal information does not identify you as an individual. For example:

  * We may collect certain non-personal data when you visit our Web Sites, such as the type of browser you are using or the referring URL; or
  * We may collect and summarize customer information in a non-personal, aggregate format for statistical and research purposes.

All references to "Web Sites" in this Privacy Policy refer to www.newdirectionsaromatics.ca, www.newdirectionsaromatics.com, or other NDA provided Web Sites.

You may choose not to provide us with your personal information. However, if you make this choice we may not be able to provide you with the product, service, or information that you requested. For example, we can only make a sales transaction under customer account for which your name and address are needed at the least.

[[Back to Top]](http://www.newdirectionsaromatics.com/#)

##  How is Your Personal Information Used? 

NDA may use your personal information for a number of different business purposes, for example to:

  * fulfill your specific requests for products, services or information;
  * provide customer support to assist you with your questions or complaints;
  * conduct surveys in order to improve our services;
  * measure and improve the effectiveness of our Web Sites or our marketing endeavours;
  * detect and protect against fraud and error;
  * track and analyze your purchases and preferences to better understand your product and service needs and eligibility;
  * tailor our online content or in-store offerings based on your preferences;
  * if you ask us, to offer and promote additional products and services we offer; and
  * for other purposes as described in this Privacy Policy.

[[Back to Top]](http://www.newdirectionsaromatics.com/#)

##  Your Consent 

NDA will collect, use, or disclose your personal information only with your knowledge and consent, except where required or permitted by law. When you choose to provide us with your personal information you consent to the use of your personal information as identified in this Privacy Policy and as may be further identified at the time of collection.

**Express Consent**

  * Sometimes you will be asked to give your express consent, such as by checking a box to indicate your consent to receive marketing communications, or by providing your signature to indicate your acceptance of the use and disclosure terms presented on an application form.

**Implied Consent**

  * Other times, we may obtain your consent implicitly when we can reasonably conclude that you’ve given consent by some action you have taken or an action you have decided not to take. Generally, this occurs where the purpose for use of your personal information would be reasonably apparent to you.

**Withdrawing Your Consent**

  * You may notify us at any time that you wish to withdraw or change your consent to our use and disclosure or your information. We will accommodate your request subject to legal and contractual restrictions related to your transactions.
  * If you have "opted in" or subscribed to one of our newsletters or mailing lists, we will always provide you the opportunity to "opt out" or unsubscribe. For example, each e-newsletter we send to you will include a link or other method to unsubscribe or decline further e-newsletters.

[[Back to Top]](http://www.newdirectionsaromatics.com/#)

##  Information NDA Collects Directly From You 

Listed here are some further examples of the ways that we collect personal information directly from you and how we use it.

**Online**

Our Web Sites can be browsed anonymously. However, to engage in certain special features or functions of our Web Sites, or to order products and services from our Web Sites, you may be asked to provide certain personal information, such as your name, email address, postal address, telephone number, or credit card information. We use this information to create your account, contact and correspond with you about your order, respond to your inquiries, and monitor functions of our Web Sites that you choose to use, such as online forums. 

**Online Forums and Customer Reviews**

Certain pages of our Web Sites, such as 'Forums', facilitate interactive discussions between users and NDA staff or agents acting on our behalf regarding products available for purchase through the Web Sites. The Customer Review functionality is provided as a rating system that offers you the chance to share your thoughts on a product. These public forums and reviews are accessible to all Web Site visitors so please use discretion when posting information to them and do not post personal information. 

**Call Centres**

NDA operates customer support call centres to accept and address your questions, concerns, or complaints. When you contact our call centres, we may ask for personal information to help us respond to your inquiry or to verify your identity. For example if you have a question about the status of a recent online order, we will ask for personal information to verify that you are the account holder. We may also monitor or record your telephone discussions with our customer support representatives for training purposes and to ensure service quality. 

**In-House Purchases**

When you purchase an NDA product, you may need to provide us with contact and payment information (such as credit card information) so that we can process your request or complete your transaction. If we also wish to use this information to send you promotional information we will ask for your express consent. 

**Returns and Exchanges**

Our goal is to ensure that you are completely satisfied with your purchase and to this end, NDA offers a Return Policy. For NDA to continue to offer our Return Policy, we ask for personal information such as your name, address, and telephone number for the purposes of detecting and preventing fraud. You may also be asked to produce photo ID, business identification number or tax identification number for verification purposes only. 

**Purchase Follow-Up and Surveys**

Following a purchase from some of our departments we may send you a follow-up letter to thank you for your business, or we may contact you to ensure that you are completely satisfied with the delivery and use of your new product. 

We may use contact information collected in-house, online, or via our customer service call centre to conduct occasional surveys and other customer research. These surveys are entirely voluntary and you may easily decline to participate. 

**Sign-Up for Newsletters or Updates**

NDA also offers a variety of newsletters and promotional communications. Should you choose to enrol we will collect your contact information, such as name and email address. This information will only be used to send you the newsletter and promotional announcements that you have requested. 

You may stop receiving newsletters and other forms of electronic marketing communication from our company at any time by following any of the following procedures:

  * You may send any one of our representatives an e-mail stating you wish to opt-out of receiving any of our electronic marketing communications.
  * You may also do this by clicking the 'Unsubscribe' link within any of the electronic newsletters that are sent out to you.
  * Or you may do this by going to our Newsletter page on our website and following the instructions there to remove your email from our list.

Our subscriber list is never sold or rented to other parties.

**Participate in a Contest or Promotion**

From time to time, we may run contests or promotions. If you participate, you may be asked for contact information as well as additional optional survey information (for example, product preferences). Personal information from contest entries will be used only to administer the contest and contact you if you win. For research and analysis purposes, we may also summarize contest survey information in a manner that no longer identifies individual participants. All contests and promotions are subject to this Privacy Policy and the rules that will be available with each particular campaign. Some contests are conducted by third parties and will be subject to the third party’s policies.

[[Back to Top]](http://www.newdirectionsaromatics.com/#)

##  Information NDA Collects Automatically 

In some cases, we automatically collect certain information:

**Our Web Sites**

When using our Web Sites, we may collect the Internet Protocol (IP) address of your computer, the IP address of your Internet Service Provider, the date and time you access our Web Sites, the Internet address of the Web site from which you linked directly to our Web Site, the operating system you are using, the sections of the Web Site you visit, the Web Site pages read and images viewed, and the content you download from the Web Site. This information is used for Web Site and system administration purposes and to improve the Web Sites.

**Cookies**

The Web Site uses "cookies", a technology that installs a small amount of information on a Web Site user's computer to permit the Web Site to recognize future visits using that computer. Cookies enhance the convenience and use of the Web Site. For example, the information provided through cookies is used to recognize you as a previous user of the Web Site, to offer personalized Web page content and information for your use, to track your activity at the Web Site, to respond to your needs, and to otherwise facilitate your Web Site experience. You may choose to decline cookies if your browser permits, but doing so will affect your use of the Web Site and prevent you from making purchases on our Web Site.

**Web Site Tracking Information**

We may use scripts from third parties which compile tracking information reports regarding Web Site user demographics, Web Site traffic patterns, and Web Site purchases. None of the tracking information in these reports can be connected to the identities or other personal information of individual users.

**Links to Other Web Sites**

Our Web Site may contain links to other Web sites or Internet resources which are provided solely for your convenience and information. When you click on one of those links you are contacting another Web site or Internet resource. NDA has no responsibility or liability for, or control over, those other Web sites or Internet resources or their collection, use and disclosure of your personal information. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of those other Web sites to learn how they collect and use your personal information.

[[Back to Top]](http://www.newdirectionsaromatics.com/#)

##  Does NDA Share Your Information? 

NDA does not sell or rent our customers’ personal information to any other party. However, in the normal course of business we may share some of your personal information within our corporate family and with third parties acting on our behalf or as permitted or required by law.

Some of these operations may result in personal information collected by NDA being stored or processed outside of Canada and, as a result, your personal information may be accessible to law enforcement and regulatory authorities in accordance with the law of these foreign jurisdictions.

**Service Providers**

NDA may use third parties to manage one of more aspects of our business operations, including the processing or handing of personal information. When we do use an outside company, we use contractual or other appropriate means to ensure that your personal information is used in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy.

For example, we may share personal information with third parties to perform services on our behalf such as: fulfilling online orders, processing non-cash payments, sending marketing communications, servicing products, conducting research surveys, verifying and validating information that you have provided to us, delivering products, and providing customer support services.

NDA has taken precautions to prevent the fraudulent use of your information on our Web Sites. NDA has adopted industry standard authentication procedures to ensure your protection while shopping with us online. This includes, but is not limited to, contacting financial institutions or credit reporting agencies to ensure the authenticity of your credit card and to validate your credit card billing information.

**Information Shared Amongst NDA, Affiliates, Subsidiaries and Divisions**

NDA may share personal information gathered on our Web Sites with subsidiaries, affiliates or divisions for internal business purposes in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If NDA shares your information within its corporate family, we will ensure that your information continues to be used only in accordance with this Privacy Policy and your expressed choices.

**Product Safety Recalls**

In the event we receive notice from a manufacturer of a product safety recall, we may provide your contact information, limited to name, address, and telephone number, to the manufacturer so that they may notify you of the recall and supply details of any replacement or repair programs. This transfer or your contact information will occur only for recalls that may impact your personal safety or impair the functionality of the product you purchased from us.

**Sale or Transfer of All or Part of NDA**

Any information we have about you may be transferred or disclosed to a purchaser or prospective purchaser in the event of a sale, assignment, or other transfer of all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to ensure that the transferee uses your information in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy.

**Legal Disclosure**

NDA may disclose your information as permitted or required by law. For example, we may be compelled to release information by a court of law or other person or entity with jurisdiction to compel production of such information. If we have reasonable grounds to believe information could be useful in the investigation of improper or unlawful activity, we may disclose information to law enforcement agencies or other appropriate investigative bodies.

[[Back to Top]](http://www.newdirectionsaromatics.com/#)

##  How Does NDA Protect Your Information? 

The security of your personal information is a high priority for NDA. We maintain appropriate safeguards and current security standards to protect your personal information, whether recorded on paper or captured electronically, against unauthorized access, disclosure, or misuse. For example, electronic records are stored in secure, limited-access servers; we employ technological tools like firewalls and passwords; and we ensure our employees are trained on the importance of maintaining the security and confidentiality of personal information.

**PCI Compliance**

NDA is PCI (Payments Card Industry) compliant meaning that all your credit card information is handled, stored and processed within strict protocols and guidelines that have been established by the PCI Security Standards Council.

**SSL Technology**

Our Web Sites use encryption technology, such as Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) from Thawte, to protect your personal information during data transport. SSL encrypts your personal information such as your name, address, and credit card number.

**Mcafee Secure Certification**

Our Web Sites have received a Mcafee Secure certificate which ensures that our Web Sites are scanned daily by a third party (Mcafee) to verify that they meet industry standards for online security.

**Choosing a Password**

When you create an online account on our Web Sites, you need to select a personal password. To maximize your level of protection, you should choose at least 5 characters including a combination of both letters and numbers. You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your password and any account information. NDA will never send an unsolicited communication asking you for your password or requesting that you update your account credentials.

[[Back to Top]](http://www.newdirectionsaromatics.com/#)

##  How Can You Verify Your Information? 

You may check your information to verify, update, or correct it, and to have any obsolete information removed. If you created an account on one of our Web Sites, you can access and change your online account profile yourself. You can also ask to review any of the information that we have retained, how we have used it, and to whom we have disclosed it at any time by contacting us. Subject to certain exceptions prescribed by law, and provided we can authenticate your identity, you will be given reasonable access to your personal information, and will be entitled to challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and to have it amended as appropriate. You may also ask us to change your preferences regarding how we use or disclose your information, or let us know that you do not wish to receive any further communication from us.

[[Back to Top]](http://www.newdirectionsaromatics.com/#)

##  When is Your Information Removed?

We keep your information only as long as we need it for legitimate business purposes and to meet any legal requirements. We have retention standards that meet these parameters. We destroy your information when it is no longer needed, or we remove your personally identifiable information to render it anonymous.

[[Back to Top]](http://www.newdirectionsaromatics.com/#)

##  Contacting NDA

If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about the privacy practices of our organization please contact us at the following:

  * Email: info@newdirectionsaromatics.com
  * Telephone: 1-800-246-7817
  * Mail: New Directions Aromatics Inc.   
6781 Columbus Road  
Mississauga, Ontario  
Canada, L5T 2G9 

We will respond to your request or investigate your concern as quickly as we can, but no later than 30 days from the date of receipt of your query.

**Important Reminder About E-mail Communications**

Please remember that email sent over the public Internet is not secure. If you send an email directly to us from your own email account the contents will not be encrypted. We strongly recommend that you do not send sensitive information (like a credit card number) to us via unencrypted email. NDA is not responsible for any transmission by you of any personal information over the public Internet.

[[Back to Top]](http://www.newdirectionsaromatics.com/#)

##  Will this Privacy Policy Change? 

**Last Update: October 26, 2010**

To accommodate changes in our services, changes in technology, and legal developments, this Privacy Policy may change over time without notice to you. We may add, change, or remove portions of the Privacy Policy when we feel it is appropriate to do so. We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy periodically. Each time you submit personal information or use our services you agree to be bound by the then current terms of the Privacy Policy. Whenever we update the Privacy Policy we will change the date to indicate when the changes were made.

[[Back to Top]](http://www.newdirectionsaromatics.com/#)
